Guide to the William F. Anselm Collection of New York University Memorabilia MC.248
New York University Archives
William F. Anselm Collection of New York University Memorabilia
1932-1991
1932-1938
New York University Archives
Anselm, William F.
MC.248
1.17 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 1 half manuscript box, 1 card box, and 2 folders in shared housing
The William F. Anselm Collection of New York University Memorabilia contains ephemera and publications dating from William F. Anselm's tenure as a student at New York University (Engineering '36). As a student, Anselm was active in Greek life as a member of the Delta Phi fraternity and the Inter-Fraternity Council. He was also a member of Scabbard and Blade, a military honor society, and the ROTC Rifle and Pistol Club.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Office of Alumni Relations in circa 2014. The accession number associated with this collection is 14.032. In November 2024, William (Bill) Anselm, William F. Anselm's son, donated an accretion; the accession number associated with this gift is 2025.028.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged chronologically in two series:
Series I: Printed Materials
Series II: Objects
Biographical Note
William F. Anselm was born in Staten Island in 1914. He studied Electrical Engineering at New York University, graduating with a Bachelor of Science degree in 1936. As a student, Anselm was active in Greek life as a member of the Delta Phi fraternity and the Inter-Fraternity Council. He was also a member of Scabbard and Blade, a military honor society, and the ROTC Rifle and Pistol Club. After graduating from NYU, he worked for General Electric.
Sources:
1. New York University. The Violet. New York: Graduating Class of 1936, 1936. New York University Archives, Elmer Holmes Bobst Library.
2. New York University College of Engineering. Directory of Alumni. University Heights, New York: New York University, June 1950.
Related Materials
Guide to the Albert W. Ferris Papers (MC 183)
Guide to the Ira S. Kaye Scrapbook (MC 80)
Scope and Contents
The collection contains ephemera and publications dating from William F. Anselm's tenure as a student at New York University (Engineering '36). Most of the materials were created by NYU between 1932 and 1938. These materials include invitations and programs for events hosted by the university or groups associated with it, including the military honor society Scabbard and Blade, the ROTC program, and the Engineering Societies. Other materials include assorted issues of the New York University Medley, a student magazine, NYU football ticket stubs and programs, and a purple quill pen labeled "NYU." A few items in the collection were not created by NYU, most of which are programs from New York City theatrical productions that Anselm presumably attended.
College students -- New York (N.Y.); Greek letter societies.; New York University. School of Engineering and Science; New York University -- Students; New York University. Reserve Officer Training Corps -- History; Delta Phi; Scabbard and Blade Fraternity
- Series I: Printed Material, 1932-1991; 0.25 Linear Feet in one half manuscript box
  Scope and Contents
  Series I includes invitations and programs for events hosted by the university or groups associated with it, including the military honor society Scabbard and Blade, the ROTC program, and the Engineering Societies. Other materials include assorted issues of the New York University Medley, a student magazine, NYU football ticket stubs and programs.
  - New York University Medley, various issues, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bond to NYU from William Killian Anselm, May 8, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Notice of Promotion to Corporal in the ROTC NYU, October 12, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Proclamation of Induction in Delta Phi, February 20, 1933 (Box Shared University Archives 155, Folder 8)
  - Invitation to Sigma Phi Beta Formal, May 13, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Program for Autumn Crocus (play), 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Certificate of Membership in Scabbard and Blade, E Company, 6th Regiment, December 7, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - NYU Engineering Societies Techni-Frolic invitation, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ROTC Formal Dinner Dance programs, 1935-07-13 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Invitation to Summer Formal of the Gamma Chapter of Delta Phi, circa 1935 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Scabbard and Blade annual military ball, 1935, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Delta Phi Fraternity House Photograph, circa 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Delta Phi Fraternity Photograph, circa 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - ROTC Annual Field Day invitation and program, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Baccalaureate Service programs, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Commencement program and invitation, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - List of the Box Holders for the 10th Annual Military Ball, circa 1936 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - NYU Bulletin -- Program for the 104th Commencement, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Invitation to Scabbard and Blade Eleventh Annual Military Ball, April 24, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Scabbard & Blade 11th Annual Military Ball Photograph, April 24, 1936 (Box Shared University Archives 154, Folder 8)
  - NYU Report Card, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Inter-Fraternity Council Informal Dance, 1936, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Playbill for Yes, My Darling Daughter, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - NYU Football ticket stubs and schedule, 1937, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - NYU Directory of Alumni, May 1940 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 25th Anniversary, Class of 1936 Photograph, May 19, 1961 (Box Shared University Archives 154, Folder 8)
  - The Delta Phi Record -- Vol 55, No.1, Fall 1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Delta Phi Record -- Vol 55, No.1, Winter 1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - NYU 1936 EEs 25th Annual Reunion Binder, May 19, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 104th Commencement Reunion Documents, July 26, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Booklet of Photographs of University Heights Campus, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Delta Phi Summer Formal invitations, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Program for Naughty-Naught (play), undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Waldorf-Astoria cocktail napkin, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - East 148th St. Restaurant Corp. business card, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series II: Objects, 1935-1936, undated; 0.5 Linear Feet in one card box
  Series II includes a badge with ribbons for representation of the Floor Committee for the 1936 Military ball; a name badge with ribbon for the 1936 Engineering Demonstration Day; a commemorative football button; and a purple quill pen labeled "NYU."
  - Floor Committee, Military Ball name badge and ribbon, 1935-04-26 (Box 2)
  - Engineering Demonstration Day name badge and ribbon, 1936 March 7 (Box 2)
  - "N.Y.U. Beat Fordham" button, undated (Box 2)
  - NYU quill pen, undated (Box 2)